Preliminary guide to the Elizabeth "Betita" Sutherland Martínez papers M1854
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- 12. National Association for Chicana and Chicano Studies [NACCS]
  Also known as NACS.
  - NACCS, 2000-2001 (Box 159, Folder 1)
  - NACCS 2002, Multiculturalism 1994 (Box 159, Folder 2)
  - Haiti, Police, NACCS [National Association for Chicana and Chicano Studies], 1996-1997 (Box 158, Folder 3)
- 13. Teaching
  - San Mateo College, Syllabi, Sonoma, Emporium (Box 137, Folder 4)
  - Distribution-Mexico, Video-evaluations, Chicago:fuego, Sharing legacy, Ideology + nationalism + multiculturalism Hayward-Cal State, Teaching ideas (Box 136, Folder 4)
  - The line between us, San Francisco State University ethnic studies, Academic jobs general, Bannerman fellowship, Community College general (Box 87, Folder 3)
  - Chicano course- Antioch Spring, Newsclippings, 1975 (Box 60, Folder 3)
  - Killing of Gilberto Ramos. 4/11/75 intro to Chicano studies (Box 60, Folder 2)
  - Textbook articles, data (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - WMS 375-review class 1992, es 3210 Intro to Chicana/Latina Studies (Box 25, Folder 5)
  - CCAC reader, CCAC course, 1994 (Box 25, Folder 4)
  - Race, sex, and class Fall, 1992 (Box 25, Folders 1-3)
  - Course '92 ideas (Box 24, Folder 6)
  - Articles on women + sexism for courses (Box 24, Folder 5)
  - Reader for race, sex, class- Spring, 1992 (Box 24, Folders 3-4)
  - Race, class + gender Spring, 1992 (Box 24, Folder 2)
  - Articles on race (for teaching) (Box 24, Folder 1)
  - CSUH Summer 1997 WOST 3410 Women, War + Revolution (Box 23, Folder 5)
  - Articles on gender (for teaching) (Box 23, Folder 4)
  - Women, War + Revolution reader, 1997 (Box 23, Folders 1-3)
  - Women, War + Revolution final (Box 22, Folder 5)
  - Ethnic studies: Women, War + Revolution (Box 22, Folder 4)
  - Latinas course, Reader for intro-Chicano/Latina Studies Fall, 1996 (Box 22, Folders 1-3)
  - Syllabi on Chicanos, CSU Summer '97-ops. 5/3/96 coc panel Lane College (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Intro to Chicana/Latina studies, Women, War + Revolution (Box 21, Folder 4)
  - CSU Hayward 1989, Course outlines + bound reader- Latinas 1996 (Box 21, Folder 3)
  - Contemporary Mexico (Box 21, Folder 2)
  - Women 485-Martinez (Box 21, Folder 1)
  - Reader for "women as agents of social change" (Box 20, Folders 6-7)
  - Civil rights movement course-Spring, 1990 (Box 20, Folder 5)
  - Fall '89 Latin American women CSH, Women as agents of social change 9/2/91, Spring '91-Sonoma (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Quiz #2. civil rights course other syllabi ideas. CSH- fall '89-Latinas student papers (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Civil rights movement (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Ethnic Studies/Latina course (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Workshop #7 (Box 19, Folder 5)
  - Workshop #6, Writers workshop. Peace and Freedom assignment (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Writers workshop (Box 19, Folder 3)
  - History of peoples of color-S.F State, 1989 (Box 19, Folder 2)
  - Latinas-bibliography, ES 3210-bibliography + videos (Box 19, Folder 1)
  - Latina writers! Sonoma ops. Lat lit #2 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Tony Platt S.W 202 Fall, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Bibliography, Armagh women (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Sonoma Spring/Fall 1992-ops, Sonoma State: women social changes, Sonoma syllabi (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Examination bluebooks, notes, newsclippings, etc. (Box 16, Folder 1)
- 14. Gubernatorial campaign, Peace & Freedom Party
  - Governor Campaign: fundraising, outreach/correspondence, Study documents (Box 93, Folder 3)
  - Peace and Freedom Governor campaign (Box 41, Folder 3)
  - Martinez for governor: Peace and Freedom Party, 1982 (Box 38, Folder 4)
- 15. Tours, lectures, screenings, conferences
  - 15.1 Addenda: 1991-1995 lectures, speeches, other engagements
    - "The 60's" - New College, Women, 1995-12-10 (Box 193, Folder 12)
    - Julia Curry's class U.C. Berkeley, 1995-12-05 (Box 193, Folder 13)
    - Georgetown University, 1995-01 (Box 195, Folder 1)
    - Panel, Racism, 1995-11-04 (Box 195, Folder 2)
    - Youth Panel, 1995-10-27 (Box 195, Folder 3)
    - Occidental, 1995-10-23 (Box 195, Folder 4)
    - SF State 9/21 - Raza Women (Box 195, Folder 5)
    - Mim. - Wisc. - Indiana, 1995-10 (Box 195, Folder 6)
    - Mata - Nebraska, 1995-09-09 (Box 195, Folder 7)
    - Sarah Lawrence, 1995-01-07 (Box 195, Folder 8)
    - Notre Dame, 1995-10-10 (Box 195, Folder 9)
    - SF State Social Work 5/28 Grad (Box 195, Folder 10)
    - Race Confererence 5/12 - 13/95, 1995 (Box 195, Folder 11)
    - SHTO, Asian Latina, 1995-05-19 (Box 195, Folder 12)
    - Jefferson H.S., 1995-05-05 (Box 195, Folder 13)
    - SF State, 1995-05-11 (Box 195, Folder 14)
    - UCSF, 1995-05-02 (Box 195, Folder 15)
    - U.C. Berkeley, 1995-04-21 (Box 195, Folder 16)
    - Kent State, 1995-04-24 (Box 195, Folder 17)
    - Boulder, CO - U.C., 1995-04-19 (Box 195, Folder 18)
    - MEChA, 1995-04-08 (Box 195, Folder 19)
    - U. of Va., 1995-04-05 (Box 195, Folder 20)
    - Teach-in Hayward, 1993-03-27 (Box 195, Folder 21)
    - USF, 1995-03-04 (Box 195, Folder 22)
    - U.C. Berkeley Librarians, 1995-02-24 (Box 195, Folder 23)
    - Sacramento, 1995-01-27 (Box 195, Folder 24)
    - Chicano Speaking Engagements (Box 195, Folder 25)
    - Panel, Chiapas, 1994-01-13 (Box 195, Folder 26)
    - Santa Cruz, 1994-01-25 (Box 195, Folder 27)
    - Stanford, 1994-03-08 (Box 195, Folder 28)
    - Santa Cruz, 1994-03-09 (Box 195, Folder 29)
    - Sacramento, 1994-03-10 (Box 195, Folder 30)
    - Gavilan College, 1994-03-17 (Box 195, Folder 31)
    - MCC, 1994-03-23 (Box 195, Folder 32)
    - Laney 4/27 (Box 196, Folder 1)
    - 8/94 (Box 196, Folder 2)
    - Cal State Fullerton, 1994-09-30 (Box 196, Folder 3)
    - City College, 1994-10-05 (Box 196, Folder 4)
    - Chicano Flier (Box 196, Folder 5)
    - Casa Magdalena Mora, 1994-10-10 (Box 196, Folder 6)
    - Wash. State Univ. - Pullman, 1994-10-12 (Box 196, Folder 7)
    - Spokane, WA, 1993-10-13 (Box 196, Folder 8)
    - SNCC Contradictions, 1994-10-15 (Box 196, Folder 9)
    - Sharon's Workshop, 1994-10-23 (Box 196, Folder 10)
    - Anti-racist Workshops 10/23 + 12/11 (Box 196, Folder 11)
    - Robert Allen's Class - U.C. Berkeley, 1994-11-29 (Box 196, Folder 12)
    - Arroyo Books, 1994-05-01 (Box 196, Folder 13)
    - Cal State Northridge, 1994-05-03 (Box 196, Folder 14)
    - Occidental, 1994-05-03 (Box 196, Folder 15)
    - 5 de Mayo, Yerba Buena, 1994-05-04 (Box 196, Folder 16)
    - SF State, 1994-05-05 (Box 196, Folder 17)
    - Castro Valley H.S., 1994-05-05 (Box 196, Folder 18)
    - New College Grad., 1994-06-03 (Box 196, Folder 19)
    - Wesleyan, 1993-11-11 (Box 196, Folder 20)
    - U.C. Irvine, 1993-11-16 (Box 196, Folder 21)
    - Eric Mar's Class 11/17 (Box 196, Folder 22)
    - Santa Cruz Core Class, 1993-11-19 (Box 196, Folder 23)
    - Sharon, 1993-11-23 (Box 196, Folder 24)
    - U.C. Berkeley - Carlo's Class, 1993-11-30 (Box 196, Folder 25)
    - NY, 1993-11 (Box 196, Folder 26)
    - Manning Marable, 1993-12-03 (Box 196, Folder 27)
    - Movimiento Estudiantil Chicano de Aztlan (Box 196, Folder 28)
    - Arc - Writing Course, 1991-10 (Box 196, Folder 29)
    - SNEEJ - Writing, 1994-04-24 (Box 196, Folder 30)
    - White Women/Racism (Box 196, Folder 31)
    - Mission Cultural Center, 1992 (Box 196, Folder 32)
    - Pledge of Res., 1992-01-16 (Box 196, Folder 33)
    - American River, 1992-02-28 (Box 196, Folder 34)
    - San Diego, 1992-03-02 (Box 196, Folder 35)
    - San Antonio, 1992-03-05 (Box 196, Folder 36)
    - Fresno, 1992-03-13 (Box 196, Folder 37)
    - Laney College, 1992-03-19 (Box 196, Folder 38)
    - Panel on PC, 1992-03-20 (Box 196, Folder 39)
    - Womens Day, Women's Palestinian, 1992-03-21 (Box 197, Folder 1)
    - UC Berkeley, 1992-03-30 (Box 197, Folder 2)
    - La Pena, 1992-04-05 (Box 197, Folder 3)
    - Hal Jamison/Berke, 1992-04-09 (Box 197, Folder 4)
    - Oberlin, 1992-04-12 (Box 197, Folder 5)
    - Los Angeles 4/15-20, 1992 (Box 197, Folder 6)
    - H2 Verdict Rally, 1992-04-16 (Box 197, Folder 7)
    - Hispanic Journalists, 1992-04 (Box 197, Folder 8)
    - Eastern Washington, Cheney, 1992-05-01 (Box 197, Folder 9)
    - Middleburg, 1992-05-05 (Box 197, Folder 10)
    - Richmond High, 1992-05-08 (Box 197, Folder 11)
    - Latino Forum on L.A., 1992-05-27 (Box 197, Folder 12)
    - Dolores Park Rally, 1992-05-08 (Box 197, Folder 13)
    - Lath Banquet, 1992-05-29 (Box 197, Folder 14)
    - CHPP ST., 1992-06-11 (Box 197, Folder 15)
    - Supreme Court. 1992 decision, 1992-06-29 (Box 197, Folder 16)
    - Peace + Dignity Run, 1992-07-31 (Box 197, Folder 17)
    - MALCS, 1992-08-04 (Box 197, Folder 18)
    - Why the left? La Pena, 1992-08-20 (Box 197, Folder 19)
    - Chicano Moratorio, 1992-08-30 (Box 197, Folder 20)
    - R.A.W. A.I.M., 1992-09-13 (Box 197, Folder 21)
    - Watsonville, 1992-08-30 (Box 197, Folder 22)
    - Chicana Foundation, 1992-09-19 (Box 197, Folder 23)
    - U.C. Berkeley, 1992-09-22 (Box 197, Folder 24)
    - Univ. of Ill. Latinos, 1922-10-22 (Box 197, Folder 25)
    - Champagne, 1992-10-22 (Box 197, Folder 26)
    - Midwest Scholars (Box 197, Folder 27)
    - U.C. Santa Cruz, 1992-11-16 (Box 197, Folder 28)
    - Loyola Panel: Media, 1992-10-25 (Box 197, Folder 29)
    - Loyola: Tues. Columbus Class, 1992-10-26 (Box 198, Folder 1)
    - Cult. Center U.I.C., 1992-10-26 (Box 198, Folder 2)
    - Fuerza Unida Tribunal, 1992-11-11 (Box 198, Folder 3)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 198, Folder 4)
    - Banela Talk, 1992-11-19 (Box 198, Folder 5)
    - Berkeley High, 1992-12-07 (Box 198, Folder 6)
    - MCC Panel, 1992-12-20 (Box 198, Folder 7)
    - ARC Conference, 1993-01-13 (Box 198, Folder 8)
    - Oregon 5/17-19/93 (Box 198, Folder 9)
    - Apthekel, 1993-05-15 (Box 198, Folder 10)
    - Angela Davis San Diego, 1993-05-12 (Box 198, Folder 11)
    - Uinversity of Oregon Spring, 1993 (Box 198, Folder 12)
    - Merritt College, 1993-05-05 (Box 198, Folder 13)
    - Palo Alto, 1993-04-24 (Box 198, Folder 14)
    - West Virginia, 1993-03-31 (Box 198, Folder 15)
    - Gettysburg, PA, 1993-03-30 (Box 198, Folder 16)
    - Univ. of Richmond, 1993-03-29 (Box 198, Folder 17)
    - Houghton Michigan, 1993-03-22 (Box 198, Folder 18)
    - L.A. Book Trip, Black + Latino Store, 1993-02 (Box 198, Folder 19)
    - Midnight Special, 1993-02 (Box 198, Folder 20)
    - UC San Diego, 1993-02-12 (Box 198, Folder 21)
    - MLK Jr. High, 1993-01 (Box 198, Folder 22)
    - MLK Jr. High, 1993-01-14 (Box 198, Folder 23)
    - Sacramento Book Party, 1992-10-15 (Box 198, Folder 24)
    - Glide (MC), 1992-10-13 (Box 198, Folder 25)
    - SF State, 1992-10-12 (Box 198, Folder 26)
    - Western Washington University, 1992-10-09 (Box 198, Folder 27)
    - SF Book Fair, 1993-11-06 (Box 198, Folder 28)
    - Haiti, 1993-10-30 (Box 198, Folder 29)
    - Berkeley U.C. Raza Day, 1992-10-23 (Box 198, Folder 30)
    - Marin Peace Center, 1993-09-20 (Box 198, Folder 31)
    - March + Rally, 1993-08-28 (Box 198, Folder 32)
    - YWCA, 1993-07-09 (Box 198, Folder 33)
    - Kendra - Memorial, 1993-06 (Box 198, Folder 34)
    - Raza Grad., 1993-06-12 (Box 198, Folder 35)
    - MLK Jr. High - Project, 1993-06 (Box 198, Folder 36)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 198, Folder 37)
  - Speeches by B. (Box 165, Folder 2)
  - Audience feedback, Screening comments, Fliers (Box 160, Folder 1)
  - 500 years/resistance, Hamilton College, Univ. of V.T 11/91, Modern Times 12/15/91, women: Indigenous, Treaty council, Go seminar on woman (Box 139, Folder 1)
  - Greens talk 4/18/91, Latino families, Carlos Munoz classes 5/91, U.C. Davis 1991, Austin, Texas speak 10/19/91, Washington State University 11/91 (Box 138, Folder 4)
  - Santa Cruz 3/23/91, Reno, Nevada 3/26/91, Panel on environmental racism + media 4/91, Indiana 1991, Vista college-4/91 (Box 138, Folder 3)
  - Lat form COC, Speaking gigs, DSA talk 11/90, modern times-talk 2/16/91, Sacramento -3/8/91, Sonoma talk 3/9/91, two conference 3/91 (Box 138, Folder 2)
  - COC July 17-19, 1992 conference committee correspondence, 1992-07 (Box 138, Folder 1)
  - Left unity, The left, Socialist, San Diego, UN conference panel 2000, South Africa 2001 photos, Malcs-1998 (Box 130, Folder 4)
  - Panel/Cuba NACCS '04, NACCS '05, NACCS '06, NACCS '07. poesia, baile y cancion, Letters from young activist (Box 130, Folder 3)
  - 5/8/00-Oakland, 4/8/00-San Diego, 3/12/00 Lideres Campesinos, L.A. 2/00, 3/8 San Jose 1/29-NACCS Foco-at Stanford (Box 117, Folder 3)
  - Oakland 2/21/00 Dead, Linda Evan Arrest 10/29/00 "Sisters of fire", Police conference 10/21, National network 10/20/00, 10/5-Val Paiso, 9/13/00 Chicago U.I. Aug 29 2000, Aug 17-Eugene, OR (Box 117, Folder 1)
  - Raza day on women 11/7/99, Stanford 5/5/99, April 23 1999, Barrios unidos, Mills 3/16/1999, 12/19 anarchist café, Intellectuals for proletarian socialism, Emilio Zapata, UMSS (Box 107, Folder 2)
  - Cuba Conference 7/99, Madison, Wisconsin 10/30/99, St. Paul, Minnesota 10/29-31/99, Urban habitat 11/13/99, 1999 (Box 107, Folder 1)
  - 4/94-Monterey CSU, Intersection Vietnam book, May 8, '99,Watsonville, 6/29/99-Teschevs-V.A. La Raza-Centro legal 6/99, PRRAC 8/5/99, Stanford notes, L.A 10/6-8/99, 9/16/99-West Valley College (Box 106, Folder 4)
  - 3/21-Labor + church, San Antonio 2/3/98, Brown university, 1/99, 2/20/99 June Jordan, L.A tour-February 1999, 2/6/99-UC Berkley, 1/12/99 interview, Grace Cathedral 11/15/98. 3/6/99 Arcada, CA Humboldt State University (Box 106, Folder 3)
  - U.C. Berkeley. UNC Chapel Hill. Introduction Daniel Perlstein and Paul Lauter. "Teaching for Freedom" by Liz Aaronsohn. A note to the teacher. A request for help on freedom school research. Mississippi freedom schools (Box 101, Folder 5)
  - New Mexico trip, 1986 (Box 90, Folder 2)
  - Gulf War-Major Analyses, Trip notes New Mexico 1989-1990 (Box 89, Folder 2)
  - Trip to L.A., newsclippings, etc. (Box 88, Folder 3)
  - L.A. notebook, 1989-03 (Box 87, Folder 4)
  - International Women's Day march San Antonio, Texas, SNCC-50th North Carolina 4/15-18/10, SCC Speech 4/16 (Box 85, Folder 1)
  - Mission Cultural Center for Latino arts July 26, 2009, Catalyst Project 8/2/09, 9/24 Mills College, Inner City Struggle, LA 10/1/09 (Box 84, Folder 6)
  - "Immaculate," "Speak out" May 2, 2009, SFSU Raza Graduation 5/16/09, Arizona '09, Watsonville, Brown Berets 4/24/09, New Mexico trip, Santa Cruz 6/6/09 Viva La Causa (Box 84, Folder 5)
  - Detroit 4/16/08, San Diego 4/23/08, SDC College 4/23/08, De Anza Community College, U.C Santa Cruz 5/7/08, University of San Francisco 9/20/08, SF Foundation, Salt of the Earth, Oakland Museum (Box 84, Folder 4)
  - Los Angeles, Orange County 3/11-19/08, Humboldt 1/08 (Box 84, Folder 3)
  - 3/29/07 E. Moriz, Merritt College 3/28/07, U.C Davis 4/22/07, Ohlone 5/9/07, Merritt College 5/07, San Diego Mesa College 9/07, San Jose State, L.A. 11/20/2008, Yale 10/26-28/08 (Box 84, Folder 2)
  - Feb. 2-2007 panel, 3/1/07-Berkley afro diaspora, 2007-encore 5/31/07, L.A. 10/4/07 ICS, Teacher T4SJ, 10/13, St. Mary's College- Notre Dame-10/06 (Box 84, Folder 1)
  - UC Santa Cruz graduation, Evergreen State College, MN Spring 2007 (Box 83, Folder 6)
  - CBE 5/27/06, CSS Marcos, 9/06 Mesa, Chicano foundation 10/06 (Box 83, Folder 5)
  - Clarissa-SFSU 3/28, UCSC 4/28/06, 5/13-Grad low income, North Western-5/3/06, Foothill College 5/12, 5/24/06 SCU Hayward (Box 83, Folder 4)
  - UCSC Monday and Honoraria payment/Si Se Puedes, Northeastern University 3/6/06, Humboldt 4/6/06 Chicano 3/4, Georgia 3/2/06 (Box 83, Folder 3)
  - 11/19 U.C Santa Cruz, CSU Long Beach 10/21/05, Utep 10/19/05, L.A 10/27/05, AK Press 12/4/05, 12/16/05 Natl. Comm Dev 1/6/06 NWSA Lunch, SF State 3/28 (Box 83, Folder 2)
  - Essex College 10/14/04, L.A. 11/3-4, Hamilton 3/4/05, USF Speech 3/31/05, 5/31/05, AM Press CSU Dominguez Hills 10/27 (Box 83, Folder 1)
  - 9/18 Sacramento, UCSF 9/23/04, Parcel, Mauro, P.C U.C. Davis 10/12/04, 10/14/04 Newark (Box 82, Folder 7)
  - Radfes 6/4-6/2004, Raza books 5/17/03 San Diego, 8/5/04- Lola 790 8/22/04 NYC (Box 82, Folder 6)
  - Denver 5/18, Funding excl 6/12/ WRL 2/13 NYC, CSUN 5/6, UCSB 1/27/04, Cornell 4/27 (Box 82, Folder 5)
  - Mills 10/16/03, 11/2/03 Raza High School, 12/4/03 "long walk to freedom," 12/6/03, 2/6/03, 2/27/04 (Box 82, Folder 4)
  - Socialist left 6/23/03, Moratorium 2003, 5/2/03-Mass-veterans for peace 8/8-9/03 Evergreen College, San Jose 9/16/03, 40th March on Washington, New College 9/13/03, Indiana 9/25/03, Sacramento 7/21, Youth, Milwaukee 20/11/03 (Box 82, Folder 3)
  - 3/12/03 Contra Costa College, 2/23/02 Teacher for social justice workshop, Robert Alleo class 2003, 7/15-Houston/radio, Wilff: Watsonville 3/03, Contra Costa 5/2, UNM 4/25/03, State of Union 6/27/03 June 21, 2003-Grab escuela popular (Box 82, Folder 2)
  - Speak out, MCC-1/17/03, 3/13/03-City College, 4/26/03 N.M., Women against war, Chicano Grad SF State 5/25 (Box 82, Folder 1)
  - Haiti 8/97, Of Feb. 2, 1998, PMP- Bilingualism 5/98. PMP-Raza Graduation (Box 80, Folder 5)
  - Meeting June 20, April 29-May 2, 1970 Journey (Box 60, Folder 4)
  - Trip through North with Bev + Humbarto, contacts for "Grito " July Aug. 1968, Motive April/May 1971 (Box 58, Folder 4)
  - Swarthmore '96, Bucknell PA 9/16/96- Michigan Adrian, 10/5/96 Latina youth summit, Oct. 9, 1996 Sacramento (Box 46, Folder 5)
  - Santa Clara 4/18, Sun Microsystems, 5/3/96- Racism- Coc, May 9, 1996- City Arts, San Mateo 5/17-18, Challenging white supremacy 5/19/96 (Box 46, Folder 4)
  - Women + AA Conference 3/10/96, International Latina Day 3/14/96 U.C Berkeley, Latina Leadership Conference, New College 3/27/96, San Diego 3/28-29/96 (Box 46, Folder 3)
  - Mills College, Berkeley clips, 3/4/96 Phoenix, AZ, Black + brown, 2/4/96-Center for Arts, 2/24/96-Contra Costa (Box 46, Folder 2)
  - Raza day 11/9/1996, San Francisco book festival 11/3/96, Vanda 11/96, Ethnic studies general, UC Berkeley '99 (Box 46, Folder 1)
  - Conference: socialism and activism, 1986 (Box 40, Folder 7)
  - Premiere San Diego 2/8/90, Sacramento 2/16/96, Women (Box 40, Folders 3-4)
  - 450 years, SWOP to reimburse, Slide shows, NM Tour, Sacramento 3/31/98, Fruitvale 3/12/98, Spanish video Pescadero 11/2, L.A- Video 11/12-23, Fresno-5/10/96-97, Cabe-1998-feb. Tijuana+ San Diego 11/19/97 (Box 40, Folder 2)
  - Video: film festival, Santa Cruz film festival, San Antonio film, Video-Spanish plans, Spanish-budget+DR (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Chicago 3/22/96-Lozaro school, Mt. Diablo high school 4/19/96, 5/4/96 San Mateo, 5/5/96 Bengal heights library, Video reception, College of Marin 11/12/1997, Havana film festival, '97 San Francisco film festival/ Cineaccion (Box 39, Folder 3)
  - Spanish premiere '97 East Bay, Premiere La Pena 1/26/96, Watsonville 6/16/95, Premiere Santa Cruz 3/14/96, Premiere San Jose 3/10/96, Premiere San Antonio 2/15, Premiere L.A 2/2/96 + 4/16 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Go study / seminar (Box 28, Folders 1-2)
- 16. Countries: travel and reference
  - 16.1 Addenda: Mexico 1988
    - Mexico - Elections '88 Background (Box 191, Folder 1)
    - Mexico - Economy Dec. - Jan. 88-89 (Box 191, Folder 2)
    - Pemex (Box 191, Folder 3)
    - Mexico - Politics - Dec, - Jan. '88 - '89 (Box 191, Folder 4)
    - Mexico: Repression (Box 191, Folder 5)
    - Mexico - U.S. Relations (Box 191, Folder 6)
    - Mexico City (Box 191, Folder 7)
    - Mexico - Various Dec. - Jan. 88-89 (Box 191, Folder 8)
    - Mexico - Correspondence, 1988 (Box 191, Folder 9)
    - Mexico - Election '88 Clippings (Box 191, Folder 10)
    - Mexico Elections Right U.S. Response (Box 191, Folder 11)
    - Mexico 1988 - Clips - Note Election (Box 191, Folder 12)
    - L.A. - Mexico (Box 192, Folder 1)
    - Mexico - Elections '88 Presentation (Box 192, Folder 2)
    - Mexico Seminar (Box 192, Folder 3)
    - Non-Mexico (e.g. Latin American) Dec. Jan. 88-89 (Box 192, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 192, Folder 5)
    - Miscellaneous Clippings (Box 192, Folder 6)
    - La Crisis Global Del Capitalismo en Mexico 1968, 1985 (Box 192, Folder 7)
    - Political Realignment in Mexico (Box 192, Folder 8)
    - Critica Magazine (Box 192, Folder 9)
    - Various Articles (Box 192, Folder 10)
    - Los Conflictos Politicos en la crisis (Box 192, Folder 11)
    - The Insurgent Sociologist (Box 192, Folder 12)
    - Miscellaneous Material (Box 193, Folder 1)
    - Dialectica (Box 193, Folder 2)
    - Book Proposal: Grassroots Movements in Mexico... (Box 193, Folder 3)
    - Mexico: Cardenas, the left and the PRI (Box 193, Folder 4)
    - Radical America (Box 193, Folder 5)
    - Mexican Grassroots Social Movements (Box 193, Folder 6)
    - Punto Critico (Box 193, Folder 7)
    - Mexico Journal - Processo (Box 193, Folder 8)
    - My Personal Notes, Recuerdos (Box 193, Folder 9)
    - Miscellaneous Newspapers (Box 193, Folder 10)
    - Various Posters (Box 193, Folder 11)
  - Panama trip (Flat-box 177, Folder 1)
  - Venezuela, Haiti-2010, Honduras, Anti-gulf war (Box 150, Folder 3)
  - Venezuela, WCRC board (Box 130, Folder 5)
  - WCRC newsletter (Box 131, Folder 1)
  - Report on the Americas. Proceso. Cuadernos politico. La Vieda politica economica de nuevo gobierno. DWP presentation mexico 7/83. Mexico-linco (Box 102, Folder 3)
  - Mexico Update Notebooks (Box 101, Folder 1)
  - Nico (rural not included), Nicaragua. Artists: Rini-Nicaragua, 1980 (Box 100, Folder 2)
  - Migration. Unemployment. US solidarity: El Salvador. Corporations/imperialism. Construction workers. Mining workers. Housing. Rural scenes. People. Culture/ideology/religion. Ideas for greeting cards. Artist: Rini miscellaneous demos Nicaragua. (Box 100, Folder 1)
  - Guatemala report, The elections, Guatemala articles, Turning the screws in Central America, Unitarian Universalist service committee, Moratorium working papers no. 34, Immigration detention, Prison and jail issues, Criminal justice issues, Newsclippings (Box 94, Folder 2)
  - Cuba Chronology, Cuba and the United States, Analysis of Nicaragua in U.S media, Brigade organization and industry relations strategy in Bulgaria 1978-83, La sistema de domiocion en Chile bajo la dictadura militar, Discussion with Jaime Osorio, The political economy of late-imperial america, Newsclippings (Box 92, Folder 2)
  - Syria, Phoenicia, Palestine, Persia, "the Observer," "The Indians," "The Civil War" (Box 76, Folder 1)
  - Cuba tour/map, Tricontinental 25 Cine Cubano ano 1, Numero 4, Cine Cubano ano 2 numero 6, Cine Cubano ano 1 numero 2, Cine Cubano Ano 1 Numero 3, Newsclippings (Box 71, Folder 5)
  - Laos trip, Laos, Vietnam newsclippings, 1970 (Box 66, Folder 1)
  - Annuaire statistique de la Martinique 1963-1966, Bulletin de statistique mars 1968 newsclippings (Box 65, Folder 6)
  - December 24, 1969, Bulletin interier du groupe d'etudes et dc researches, Bulletin de statisque, 1967, Frantz Fanon Institute, Martinique, Histoire de l'esclavage dans les colonies franchises, On the theses of Fanon: the role of violence in the struggle for national liberation (Box 65, Folder 5)
  - La Martinique, Bulletin de Satistique, Notes on Des Iles et des hommes, Exclauge et colonisation notes, King Sugar (Box 65, Folder 4)
  - Reports on China, memorandum (Box 65, Folder 3)
  - China, Chinese brochures, Pamplets, Chinese export commodities fair, 1972 (Box 65, Folder 2)
  - People's primer uniting Panama, Panama struggle for independence, Epica task force (Box 64, Folder 3)
  - Cuba, Panama papers, Panama struggles for independence, El Diario de la genta: Somos Aztlan, Newsclippings (Box 64, Folder 2)
  - Paper samples, Africa-graphics-dupes+ rejects (Box 64, Folder 1)
  - Haiti, newsclippings, etc. (Box 63, Folder 6)
  - Panama 1975, Panama Canal Works, photos, Seers volume 5 number 1, Culture and politics: Notes from a conference by Barbara Bick (Box 63, Folder 3)